<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<link rel="self" href="/" />
	<id>/</id>
	<title>KWBlog</title>
	<rights>2018</rights>
	<updated>2018-01-24T23:02:40Z</updated>
	<subtitle>KWBlog</subtitle>
	<entry>
		<link href="/posts/20180123-new-blog" />
		<id>/posts/20180123-new-blog</id>
		<title>New Blog!</title>
		<updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my new blog!  I've had a blog &lt;a href="http://kevin-berridge.blogspot.com"&gt;on blogger&lt;/a&gt; since April 4 2007.  That's almost 11 years!  That's a long time!  After all that time, I thought I was due for a change, and I thought it would be fun to build that change myself.  Turns out it was fun!  I learned a lot of stuff that I probably should have already known, but didn't.  So let's get meta and blog about the development of this blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had three major questions to answer about how to build a new blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to host it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to &amp;quot;code&amp;quot; it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should it look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id="how-to-host-it"&gt;How To Host It&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't want to spend a lot of money, in fact, I didn't want to spend any money at all.  So the obvious choice, and indeed the one I ultimately went with, was &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the other options, all non-free, I looked at included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nearlyfreespeech.net/"&gt;NearlyFreeSpeech.Net&lt;/a&gt; - cheap basic web hosting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azure Websites - I'm a &amp;quot;Microsoft developer&amp;quot; but I've never used Azure, thought it might be fun.  But it ain't cheap, so I didn't go this route.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azure Blob Storage - Azure's version of S3 I guess?  Cheap, supports custom domains, but not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt;.  You can point a custom domain at it, but you can't setup a default document or eliminate the folder portion of the URL.  So you can't get a simple url like kevinberridge.com to work.  So, non-starter for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS S3 - Cheap, really does support custom domains it looks like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of me really likes that this is free.  But another part of me doesn't trust anything I don't have to pay at least &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; for.  And I like github, but I don't love how they seem to be eating the world.  I think I'll leave it on github, but there's a chance I might still play with moving this over to AWS S3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do have a bone to pick with github pages.  It is SO CLOSE to being great.  With &amp;quot;User pages&amp;quot; all the content files must be in the root of your repo on the master branch, full stop.  So, where do you put your actual source files then?  I wasn't comfortable putting them on the master branch in subfolders, just cause I don't know if they'd be accessible or not.  So I'm trying to put them on a separate unrelated &amp;quot;blog&amp;quot; branch.  But when you build how do you move the output from the &amp;quot;blog&amp;quot; branch over to the &amp;quot;master&amp;quot; branch?  Can you build and then do &lt;code&gt;git checkout master&lt;/code&gt;?  Or will that wipe out the output directory?  I saw someone doing something interesting but also scary with the &lt;code&gt;git subtree&lt;/code&gt; command, but ain't nobody got time for that.  So I tried to do a quick simple hack to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mv .\output ..\output # move output outside the repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git checkout master&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;robocopy ..\output . /MIR # DO NOT DO THIS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number 3 there makes the working directory exactly match the output directory (&amp;quot;mirrors&amp;quot; it), including removing files.  Oh, hey, that means it will remove the .git folder and you'll loose all your history.  Oh, and you're on the master branch now which doesn't have your source files so ALL YOUR SOURCE IS GONE.  But, oh man lucky me, I did commit the source on the master branch before I started messing with ghpages so PHEW that was close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Project pages&amp;quot; let you put the output in a &amp;quot;docs&amp;quot; folder instead of right in the root.  For some reason this isn't an option with &amp;quot;User pages&amp;quot;.  And you can't configure the name of that folder, it has to be called &amp;quot;docs&amp;quot;.  I find all of this very annoying and I still haven't come up with a solution I'm happy with.  Maybe S3 is looking better and better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed most of these hosting options are simple content hosts, not full web servers, which leads to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="how-to-code-it"&gt;How To Code It&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew I wanted to use a static content generator right off the bat.  This is a blog, there is no dynamic content here, and I'll write a new page, what?, once a week at the absolute most?  So static generator it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But oh my gosh there are a lot of options for static content generators!  Of course you've got the biggest most famous of them, &lt;a href="https://jekyllrb.com/"&gt;Ruby's Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.  I've used it before, it's easy, there's lots of templates, everyone uses it.  Obvious win.  But I don't use Ruby anymore, and honestly, I just didn't want to install it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A relative newcomer (at least to me) that seems to be getting a fair amount of attention these days is &lt;a href="http://gohugo.io/"&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, written in Go.  It looks nice and there's a ton of themes, and it's supposed to be real fast.  Sounds great.  I'm not using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another from the Node.js world was &lt;a href="https://ghost.org/"&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;.  It got lots of attention, good and bad.  I have a love/hate relationship with node though.  But this seems super popular, and they've build a whole business around the thing.  Neato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I decided to use &lt;a href="https://wyam.io/"&gt;Wyam&lt;/a&gt;.  I don't know anyone who uses it, I don't even &lt;em&gt;know of&lt;/em&gt; anyone who uses it.  It only has 5 themes.  But it's written in C#, and you can write your own themes with Razor templates, and it was very easy to get started with.  I haven't dug into it's source a ton yet, but what I have looked at seemed nice.  Though the API you use in the templates themselves is kinda weird, I haven't totally wrapped my head around it.  And the big sell is all about how composable it is, but I haven't touched any of that or seen good examples.  Whatever, I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-should-it-look-like"&gt;What Should It Look Like?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should look like this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided I wanted to do two rather contradictory things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to design and style it from scratch myself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn't want to put much time or effort into designing or styling it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for me, I knew I wanted it to be simple.  Sparse even.  You might even say &amp;quot;plain&amp;quot;, if you were my wife.  Whatever, I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href="https://purecss.io/"&gt;purecss&lt;/a&gt; and that's it.  I like pure's grid system, and I like it's responsive grids too.  I played with fonts.  I like grey.  I picked one color: red.  I think it should win a design award.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my new blog!  I've had a blog &lt;a href="http://kevin-berridge.blogspot.com"&gt;on blogger&lt;/a&gt; since April 4 2007.  That's almost 11 years!  That's a long time!  After all that time, I thought I was due for a change, and I thought it would be fun to build that change myself.  Turns out it was fun!  I learned a lot of stuff that I probably should have already known, but didn't.  So let's get meta and blog about the development of this blog!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
</feed>